AMANDA CLAIRE: All right so to tin the wire, remember we're going to put the iron onto the wire, get the wire really really hot, and remember, you want to kind of stay away from touching your soldering iron to the solder itself.
I mean, obviously you can, it's fine, but the point of soldering is not to melt the solder with the iron, it's more to heat up the metal electrical component with the iron and let the heat from the component melt the solder so it's kind of an indirect heating.
So here I am kind of heating the wire, I'm going to get it close to the solder and the solder should kind of flow over our wire here if we're lucky--oh there, it started to go.
There we go, there we go and there we go.
Now we've pretty much tinned our wire, we'll do a little bit more there, yeah, okay.
So you have a nicely tinned wire; basically, it just means that's it's coated with solder.
And since we're here, let's just might as well, let's just do the other one.
Same deal, we'll kind of get the wire hot, kind of get it near the solder and whoop, there we go.
It happens real quickly.
You'll find that this stranded copper wire--it heats up very, very fast which is good.